So, in the last video we have set up the wheat ok. So, now it is running on the localhost
5.1.73. So, let us navigate to this website. So, as we can see that in this one wheat
plus react. So, you can click on this counter. So, it is using the use state hook ok. So,
we can go to this website as well. So, for now we are going to just follow up on
it ok. Now, after this we are going to this change change to the backend directory ok.
So, control C. So, CD dot dot. So, in order to go one level back and now we are going to
change the directory to backend. So, we are going to just initialize NPM. So, NPM in
it dash y ok. So, it is a default setup for NPM. So, after this node package manager initial
setup we are going to install a bunch of packages ok. So, NPM install express. After this
we are going to just use Mongoose also because we are going to use the Mongoose database
and dot ENV. Dot ENV we are going to use for like as a middleware ok and JSON web token
to create sign in and sign on functionality ok. So, JSON web token and after this we are
going to just to use the decrypt.js in order to hash the passwords during the sign in
and login and after that we are going to use this cookie parser. So, we all know it is
a middleware and after this we are going to use this cloud memory package for uploading
the images. So, let us install this. So, it is going to install all of these packages.
So, meanwhile we are going to just check this package.json. So, it is going to install
everything. So, the type is the common JS ok. So, minimize this one. So, as you can see
that all of these dependencies has been installed like bkrip.js cloud nary cookie parser
and dot ENV expression JSON web token and Mongoose ok. So, all of these have been installed
so, we are going to use all of this right. So, let us go and sort of our backend folder
and we are going to just create our first server.js file and we are going to just write
some like sample API routes ok. So, what we are going to do here is like since we are going
to use this common JS syntax as default. So, we are going to change this as type of module
because for this one it is quite easy to use and now after this we are going to just go
inside of this backend folder and we are going to create one source folder. So, with
the name SRC and inside of this Rc we are going to just create one file which is called
as app.js. So, this is the server file which we are going to just create ok.
So, for this we are going to import the express so import express from express ok. So, control
us and we are going to just initialize our express app. So, const app equal to express.
So, after this we are going to just create a few sample routes ok. So, creating this sample
routes is quite easy. So, first we are going to just use this app.listen. So, app.listen
and inside of the app.listen we are going to just define this the port which we are going
to use to listen to all of the activities like display all the activities. So, it is going
to just listen on this local port and display the results like display all of the activities
which are going on ok. So, now let us a console log something ok. For example, for example,
console.log console.log server is running on port server is running on port 5000. So, we can
do like this go here and we are going to define our port like this ok 5000. We can also
use one variable declaration like const const port equal to 5000 and we can use this port
variable instead. So, like that ok. We can change like this so const port equal to 5000
and this port value can be used here inside of this app.listen and same for the console.log
part we can replace this port here as well. So, now in order to run our backend application
ok. So, in order to run this app.js file what we can do is go inside of this package.listen
and I have one package is called as node 1. So, you can globally install node 1 by going
inside of this terminal by quitting all the servers and then just navigate to the back
and folder and just type the NPM I NPM install node 1. So, if you use the dash g there
so, it is going to install globally. You can check this out on Google ok. So, for here
we have removed everything from here and for the testing part. So, what I am going to
do is node 1 src/app.js ok. So, I have saved here. So, now what I will do like here as
you can see that backend folder ok. So, NPM. So, we can name this as start actually
so, it would be better. So, NPM start ok. So, let us start this one. So, actually this
is not required as an internal external command. So, I think we need to install here. So,
NPM install node 1 / g sorry dash g yes. So, we have installed this node 1 package
like globally. So, NPM I node 1 dash g. So, let us start now. So, NPM start. So, if we can
see that node 1 has started and the server is running on the port 5000. So, now it is running
actually. So, yeah that is it.